# kinto behr

# data scientist / data engineer

#### PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a data professional with experience working in both modeling and engineering roles, using Python, R and SQL. No matter which side of the fence I'm on, I love writing clean, modular, well-organised code to solve challenging data problems. Please visit my website for an expanded CV.

## EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

#### **Data Scientist**

Social Research Centre | 2022 - Present

I am the technical lead on a variety of machine learning and data engineering projects including,

- Propensity and segmentation modeling, timeseries forecasting, natural language processing, Bayesian modeling (e.g. multilevel regression with poststratification), etc.
- MLOps, automating training and model deployment pipelines, implementing APIs for accessing model predictions, etc.
- ETL/ELT pipeline design and maintenance, SQL database architecture
- Development and maintenance of internal software packages, overall package ecosystem design

#### Data Engineer

Social Research Centre | 2020 - 2022

I was the lead data engineer on the SES, a large scale survey of Australian higher education students. Some of the things I worked on in this role were,

- ETL pipeline maintenance and optimisation, often massively reducing computation time (some 100x improvements with clever use of matrix algebra) and code complexity
- Process automation and simplification for scalability
- Data visualisation and dashboarding (PowerBI, Tableau) and Shiny application development
- Mentorship and technical guidance for more junior members of staff

#### Team Lead

Sidekicker | 2018 - 2020

I was in charge of the community operations team, which was responsible for ensuring that the application marketplace was running smoothly. Alongside managing 15+ casual call-centre staff, I

- · Performed data analysis using SQL and Python
- Automated core processes to save  $\sim \! 100 hrs$  of labour-time per month

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **Master of Statistics**

University of New South Wales | 2021 - 2023

- Awarded with Excellence from UNSW and placed on Dean's List (top 3%) while completing first half at University of Melbourne.
- Thesis title: Classification with Semi-Supervised Learning Algorithms
- WAM: 92%

#### **Bachelor of Arts (Honours)**

University of Melbourne | 2019

- Recieved the Hastie Prize for graduating top of my class
- Thesis title: Epistemic Relativism: The Futility of the Argument from the Criterion
- GPA: 4.0 (WAM: 87%)

#### Bachelor of Arts and Bachelor of Science

Monash University | 2013 - 2017

- Received numerous academic awards including the **Peter J. Lloyd Prize in Theoretical Physics**, the Dean's List Fellowship Award and five best in unit awards for achieving top marks across various physics courses
- Majors (minors): Philosophy (Japanese) and Physics (Mathematics)
- GPA: 3.93 (WAM: 87%)

### **SKILLS**

- Programming languages: SQL, R, Python, HTML, JavaScript (Svelte), Rust, Stan, LaTeX
- Natural languages: English (native), German (B2), Japanese (once N2 but now probably N4)
- Tools: Git, GitHub, Make, Docker, dbt, AirFlow, PowerBI, Tableau, Shiny, TensorFlow
- Soft skills: Public speaking, technical writing, mentorship